Shashi Ranjan Kumar

Senior Software Engineer

+91-9852041771 shashiranjansharma@live.in

LinkedIn Github CodePen

Profile

Innovative Senior Software Engineer offering 8.5 years of experience. Enthusiastic about developing forward-thinking solutions to tomorrow's productivity problems. Demonstrates hardworking and adaptable approach to challenges with strong analytical and critical thinking skills.

Areas of Expertise

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Typescript, Vue 3, Vue Js, Pinia, Vuex, High Chart, Jenkins, Git, Node Js, Problem Solving

Professional Experience

Senior Software Engineer – I, (Cyware Labs)

Bangalore, IN 02/2022 - present

- Implemented **Threat Defender Library** workflows offering with the threat defender collaboration network by allowing the sharing of rules, analytics, and files used in cyber threat detection, threat hunting, and threat defense.
- I also implement a Requirements-Driven Approach to Threat Intelligence Life cycle (Intelligence Requirement Sharing).
- Above features UI were implemented with Vue3 JavaScript framework with RestApi.

Software Engineer – II, (Cyware Labs)

Bangalore, IN 02/2018 - 02/2022

- Mentoring Junior Developers: Shared my knowledge and experience to guide and support junior developers.
- Stayed Updated with **Vue.js Ecosystem**: Keeping up with the latest advancements in **Vue.js**, including new features, libraries, and best practices.
- Contributed to **In House UI Library**: With my expertise i have contributed to In House Vue.js Ui library for Reusable components across the project.
- I was able to develop several key skills while contributing to the success of the company
- I was building and maintaining applications, crafting user interfaces, debugging issues, and ensuring accessibility for all users.

Software Engineer, (99tests.com)

Bangalore, IN 08/2017 - 02/2018

• As UI Developer at 99tests.com (India). Built user-friendly interfaces with AngularJS, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. Crafted visually appealing and interactive web elements for a positive user experience.

Test Engineer, (Diduce Technology)

Kolkata, IN *02/2014 - 08/2017*

• Leveraging strong analytical and problem-solving skills, I ensured software quality through manual and automated testing, planning and executing comprehensive tests, and debugging errors for improved performance.

Projects

- Business Card GeneratorApplication made for generating the VCard, Its a business card with QR code, On scanning the QR code form mobile the contact of the person will be automatically saved to the phone contact. This project is built on VueJs framework and node version 14.21. Click for Preview
- Personal Blog AppCreated a personal blog application with all CRUD operations, profile management and authentication.
 Tech: ReactJS, NodeJs.

Education

B.Tech, Electronics and Communication Engineering Rajasthan Technical University, Kota

2009-2013

I have completed my degree in Electronic and Communication in year 2013 with 69 percent of marks.